Ken Krayeske Papers 2003.0090
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Ken Krayeske Papers
1969-2009
2003.0090
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
39.0 Linear feet
The Ken Krayeske Papers consist of administrative records, publications, pamphlets, correspondence, clippings, financial records, fliers, legal documents, audio cassettes, photographs, and posters of Meriden, Connecticut based attorney and activist Ken Krayeske. The collection contains materials from 1969 to 2009, with the bulk of the collection comprised of materials from the 1990s and 2000s.
Biography
Ken Krayeske is a Meriden, Connecticut, based attorney who practices in commercial litigation and a variety of other areas of law. Krayeske is a 2010 graduate of the University of Connecticut School of Law and a 1994 graduate of Syracuse University’s Newhouse School of Public Communications.
Before entering the law Krayeske wrote for daily, weekly, and monthly newspapers and magazines, taught youth journalism, been a snowboard instructor, manufactured minor league baseball cards, worked as a deckhand on a trans-Atlantic megayacht, and campaigned for Ralph Nader. Most recently, he ran for United States Congress in Connecticut’s First Congressional District with the Connecticut Green Party in 2010.
Scope and Content Note
Materials in the collection consist of administrative records, notes, publications, pamphlets, optical disks, correspondence, magnetic disks, clippings, financial records, fliers, legal documents, maps, realia, magnetic disks (floppy disks), audio cassettes, photographs, awards, microforms, and posters. The collection contains materials from 1969 to 2009, with the bulk of the collection from the 1990s and 2000s. The collection contains materials that some may find objectionable.
Subjects in the collection include the Blue Line Trading Cards Company, Warning Track Trading Cards Company, Youth Communication, VOX, Southend Knightriders Youth Center Inc. (SKYC), A.N.S.W.E.R. Coalition, Clifford Thornton Candidacy, Ralph Nader, the Eighth Annual Youth Spirit Awards, Nevis Island, St. Kitts, Syria, Iraq, and the St. Christopher and Nevis Island Budget Address from 1994-1995. The collection also includes a wide variety of magazines and newspapers, to include The Labour Spokesman, The Democrat, The Chronicle, High Times, Sports Illustrated, The New York Pos t, The Atlantic, Penthouse, National Geographic, Scientific American, Harpers Mother Jones, Rolling Stones, Playboy, The Sun, The War Crimes Times, New York Times, The Hartford Advocate, The Waterbury Observer, The Observer St. Kitts-Nevis, The Hartford Courant, and Underground Voices.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Provenance and Acquisition
The records were donated by Ken Krayeske in installments beginning in 2003.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to various aspects of Connecticut history and politics, the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students.
For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
Krayeske, Ken; Administrative Records.; Civil actions.; Clippings (information artifacts).; Correspondence.; Ephemera.; Fliers. [printed matter]; Legal Records.; Manuscripts.; Maps.; Microfilm.; Newsletters.; Notes.; Photographs.; Publications.; Realia.
- Series I: An Inventory, 1969-2009
  - Administrative Records, Notes, Publications (Pamphlets), Optical Disks, Correspondence, Magnetic Disks, Clippings, Financial Records, Fliers, Legal Records, 1995-2003; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs, Portfolio with labeled tabs. (Box 2006-0199_1)
    Scope and Content Note
    Subjects Include: Blue Line Trading Cards Company, Warning Track Trading Cards Company, Youth Communication, VOX, Southend Knightriders Youth Center Inc. (SKYC).
    Alternative Press
  - Publications, Fliers, Clippings, Financial Records, Legal Documents, Administrative Records, 2004, 2006, 2007; 1.3 Linear feet Paperwork is organized in enclosed folders and paperclips. (Box 2007-0033_2)
    Subjects Include: March on the Pentagon March 17 2007, A.N.S.W.E.R. Coalition, Connecticut Campaign Finance Laws, Nominating Petitions for Candidates for State Offices for The Green Party: November 7, 2006 Election, Clifford Thornton Candidacy, State of Connecticut Mail-In Voter Registration, Eighth Annual Youth Spirit Awards Connecticut.
  - Notes, Publications, Map and Realia: Altoids Container, 1993, 1994, 1995; 1.0 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs, Notepads. (Box 2005-0154_3)
    Subjects Include: St. Christopher and Nevis Island Budget Address 1994-1995, Nevis Island, St. Kitts, The Observer.
  - Publications, 9 Magnetic Disks (Floppy Disks), Map, 1993, 1994, 1995; 0.25 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs. (Box 2005-0154_4)
    Subjects Include: Nevi's Historical and Conservation Society, The Labour Spokesman, The Democrat, The Chronicle, work from The Observer, Five Star Follies Musical Show Script.
  - Publications, 1989, 1992, 1995-2003; 1.3 Linear feet Organized by magazines with and without Krayeske publications. (Box 2005-0085_5)
    Subjects Include: High Times Magazine.
  - Publications, 1987, 1989, 1990, 1999-2005; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 2005-0085_6)
    Subjects Include: The New American, Smithsonian, Punk Planet, The Progressive, Sports Illustrated, New York Post The Yankee's Century, The Atlantic, Private Eye, Green Anarchy, Pent House, Content, National Geographic, Scientific American, Natural History, Harpers Magazine, Mother Jones, Print, Rolling Stones, Playboy, The Sun, Heads, Fitness, The Nation, Weird, Slime, Hit List, The Fantastic Four, The Silver Surfer, The Comic Journal, Dork, Peoples Weekly World, Home City Free Press.
  - 27 Sound Recordings (audio cassettes), 1995-2001; 0.5 Linear feet Tapes are labeled. (Box 2007-0033_7)
    Subjects Include: VASS, Dan Forbes, Paul Bowles, Charlottes's Web, Harrelson, Tibetan Freedom Fest, Rapping with Reynolds, Colin and Me, Grinspoon, The United Church of Christ in Cornwall Congregation, UFO's-Code 4, Rowland Interview, Moe Interview, Colin, Marabel.
  - Publications, Fliers, 2007-2009; 1.0 Linear feet (Box 2003-0090_8)
    Subjects Include: The War Crimes Times, Prometheus Radio Project, Maine Cyclist, Quaker Action, Prospect, The Scope, COMPAGNIE Marie Chouinard, Peace Work, CO-OP American Quarterly, New York Times, Central Connecticut Bycicle Alliance, The Hartford, The Chronicle.
  - Publications, 1997-1998; 2.0 Linear feet Organized in chronological order. (Box 2003-0090_9)
    Subjects Include: The Register Citizen
  - Publications, Clippings, 1994, 1998-1999; 2.0 Linear feet Organized in chronological order. (Box 2003-0090_10)
    Subjects Include: The Hartford Advocate, The Waterbury Observer, The Observer St. Kitts-Nevis, The Hartford Courant, Underground Voices, The Register Citizen.
  - Publications, Clippings, Notes, Handouts, 1995, 1997, 1998, 2006; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 2007-0009_11)
    Subjects Include: Cliff Thornton Media, The Daily Campus, The Hartford News, The New Haven Register, The Hartford Courant, The Quinnipac Legal Times, The Chronicle, Voter's Guide Election 2006, The Putnam Villager, The Hartford Catholic Worker, The Sunday Republican, Town Times, The Sports Page Magazine, Track Record, Eastern Connecticut Public Liberal Arts University Pamphlet, The Greater Hartford News, Warning Track Cards Advertisements, The Downtowner.
  - Administrative Records, Clippings, Handouts, Financial Records, Correspondence, Notes, Legal Documents, Publications, 1998-2002; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs. (Box 2003-0090_12)
    Subjects Include: Columbia Scholastic Press Association High School Journalism Conference, Echoes Fromt the Streets, Dow Jones Newspaper Fund, Youth Communication, VOX, Student Press Law Center, Poynter Institute, Our Piece of the Pie, Southend Community Services, Youth Street News, YO! Hartford, Civil Rights, Court Case: Eric M. Weiss and The Hartford Courant vs. Michael P. Peters and John Bazzano.
  - Publications, Clippings, Handouts, Correspondence, Notes, Administrative Records, Financial Records, 2001-2002; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs. (Box 2003-0090_13)
    Subjects Include: Issue 4 RRR, Teaching Tips, Issue 3 RRR, Educational Partners, Resource Materials for students, Southend Community Services, Potential Funding for Echoes from the Streets, Youth Communication, Our Piece of the Pie, Story Development Strategies.
  - Administrative Records, Clippings, Legal Documents, Publications, Handouts, Correspondence, Financial Records, 1996, 1998, 1999, 2000; 0.5 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs. (Box 2003-0090_14)
    Subjects Include: The Republican American, Simsbury High School Football, Warning Track Cards and Marketing, Connecticut Annual Report and Legal Measures on Drugs, The Hartford Advocate Sale, The San Francisco Bay Gaurdian.
  - Publications, Notes, 1995, 1997, 1998, 1999; 1.3 Linear feet Organized in chronological order. (Box 2003-0090_15)
    Subjects Include: The Greater Waterbury Republican American, The Sunday Republican, Town Times, 22 Reporters Notebooks.
  - Publications, Clippings, Correspondence, 1994-1996, 1997; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 2003-0090_16)
    Subjects Include: The Sunday Republican, The Waterbury Republican American, Letter to Robert Brown editor of Waterbury Republican-American.
  - Publications, 1998-1999; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 2003-0090_17)
    Subjects Include: The Hartford Advocate.
  - Administrative Records, Correspondence, Clippings, Notes, Financial Statements, Postcards, Publications, 2001, 2002, 2003; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs. (Box 2003-0090_18)
    Subjects Include: Southend Community Services, Our Piece of the Pie, Sex Education, Look Up Hook Up, Student Press Law Center, Relocation of Echoes from the Streets, Columbia University Trip, Youth Street News, YO! Hartford, Trek for Knowledge 2002, PepNet 2002.
  - Legal Documents, November 2008; 0.25 Linear feet Labeled folder (Box 2003-0090_19)
    Subjects Include: Nominating Petitions for Scott Deshefy for Congress.
  - Legal Documents, November 2008; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 2003-0090_20)
    Subjects Include: Nominating Petitions for Ralph Nader for President, Ralph Nader letter.
  - Photographs, Optical Disks, Award, 2001-2002; 1.3 (Box 2003-0090_21)
    Subjects Include: Our Piece of the Pie Award, Governor Rowland, Echoes from the Streets.
  - Photographs, Microforms, 2001, 2002; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 2003-0090_22)
    Subjects Include: UCONN Basketball, Hartford Basketball, Sports, Miscellaneous.
  - Publications, Photographs, 2002-2007; 1.3 Linear feet Two portfolios (Box 2003-0090_23)
    Subjects Include: Echoes from the Streets (Winter 2007, Summer 2006)
  - Administrative Records, Fliers, Notes, Publications, Financial Records, Posters, Pamphlets, Correspondence, Awards, 2004-2006; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs and portfolios. (Box 2003-0090_24)
    Subjects Include: Our Piece of the Pie, Echoes from the Streets, Southend Community Services, The Hartford Advocate, Echoes from the Streets materials and curriculum.
  - Administrative Records, Fliers, Notes, Publications, Financial Records, Posters, Pamphlets, Correspondence, Optical Disks, Magnetic Disks, 2004-2006; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 2003-0090_25)
    Subjects Include: Our Piece of the Pie, Echoes from the Streets, Southend Community Services, The Hartford Advocate, Echoes from the Streets materials and curriculum, Book of Lists.
  - Administrative Records, Legal Documents, Financial Records, Clippings, Notes, Correspondence, Optical Disks, Magnetic Disks, Postcards, 1969-2006; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs. (Box 2003-0090_26)
    Subjects Include: Connectitcut Communitiy Providers Association, Qimin Liu, ECSU, ECSU Soccer 1969, IT Security: Ivestigation and Prosecution of Cyber Crimes, Progressive Magazine, Trip to Syria, Abu Kamal, Iraq War, New York Times, Punk Planet, Echoes from the Streets.
  - Administrative Records, Legal Documents, Financial Records, Clippings, Notes, Correspondence, Optical Disks, Magnetic Disks, Postcards, Relia, 1992-2006; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs. (Box 2003-0090_27)
    Subjects Include: Denny Lane Story, The Boston Freedom Rally, War on Drugs, High Times Articles, Dr. Lester Grinspoon, Cliff Thronton for Governor, Green Party, Relia: Campaign Buttons.
  - Legal Documents, 2008; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 2003-0090_28)
    Subjects Include: Nominating Petitions for Candidates for Presidential Elector: Ralph Nader
  - Administrative Records, Correspondence, Publications, Manuscript, Notes, 1983-1994; 1.3 Linear feet Notebooks and folders with labeled tabs. (Box 2003-0090_29)
    Subjects Include: Survival as the Goal of Wisdom, Holy Cross High School, Eye Fish in a See of Word (An Anthology Syracuse University), The Daily Orange, Syracuse Herald Journal, USA Today, The Cross Chronicle, College Work (Syracuse Uconn).
  - Administrative Records, Correspondence, Publications, Manuscript, Notes, Postcards, Photographs, 1991-1994; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 2003-0090_30)
    Subjects Include: USA Today, High Times, Times Magazine, College Work (Syracuse Uconn).